WeiQin Chuah

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/weiqin Github: github.com/weiqin

Webpage: https://waychin-weiqin.github.io/

ABOUT ME

I am a highly motivated and dedicated Ph.D. graduate from RMIT University, Australia, with a background in Engineering and Computer Science. Currently, I hold the position of a post-doctoral researcher at the same institution, where my research is centred on domain generalization, representation learning, and geometric computer vision. My research findings hold practical relevance across diverse domains, including medical imaging, fault detection, robotics, augmented reality, and autonomous driving.

Email: weiqin5645@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 424 095 691

Professional Experience

•	RMIT University / Ford Motor Company Research Assistant (Deep Learning, Computer Vision) Research and development of an intelligent and automated visual inspection system for self-piercing rivets.	Melbourne, Australia Oct 2022 - Current
•	RMIT University / Bondi Labs Casual Researcher (Deep Learning, Computer Vision) Research and development of an intelligent and automated visual inspection system for vet-assistive technology.	Melbourne, Australia Sept 2022 - Oct 2022
•	RMIT University Mechatronics Engineering Intern (Machine Learning, Image Processing, Sensor Fusion) Research and development of an intelligent cow screening and cleaning system	Melbourne, Australia Dec 2017 - Feb 2018
•	Aubot Mechanical Engineer Intern (Mechanical Design) Research and development of a 6 degree of freedom assistant robotic arm, Jeva	Melbourne, Australia Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

Publications

• Single Domain Generalization via Normalized Cross-correlation Based Convolutions IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) 2024 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, D Suter, A Bab-Hadiashar

• An Information-Theoretic Method to Automatic Shortcut Avoidance and Domain Generalization for Dense Prediction Tasks

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI) 2023 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar, D Suter

• Towards Building a Vet-Assist System: Animal pose estimation and counting walking steps
Australasian Conference on Robotics and Automation (ACRA) 2022

WQ Chuah, A Bab-Hadiashar, R Tennakoon, F Zambetta, R Hoseinnezhad, J Hall, J Marshall, S Smith, M Stevenson

• ITSA: An Information-Theoretic Approach to Automatic Shortcut Avoidance and Domain Generalization in Stereo Matching Networks

IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2022 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar, D Suter

• Semantic Guided Long Range Stereo Depth Estimation for Safer Autonomous Vehicle Applications IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 2022

WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, D Suter, A Bab-Hadiashar

• Deep Learning-Based Incorporation of Planar Constraints for Robust Stereo Depth Estimation in Autonomous Vehicle Applications

IEEE Transactions on Itelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 2021 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar

Machine Vision-Enabled Traffic Controller for Safer and Smoother Traffic Flow Around Construction Sites
 IEEE Intelligent Transportation Systems Conference (ITSC) 2019 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar

• State Transition for Statistical SLAM Using Planar Features in 3D Point Clouds Sensors, Volume 19, Issue 1614, 2019

AK Gostar, C Fu, WQ Chuah, MI Hossain, R Tennakoon, A Bab-Hadiashar, R Hoseinnezhad

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Post-graduate

Computational Machine Learning

Tutor / Lab Demonstrator

RMIT University 2021 - 2022

RMIT University Deep Learning

Tutor / Lab Demonstrator

Semester 2 2022

Under-graduate

Machine Learning

Tutor / Lab Demonstrator

RMIT University 2021 - 2022

Digital Fundamentals RMIT University Lab Demonstrator Semester 1 2021

Mechatronics Principle Teaching Assistant

RMIT University Semester 1 2020

EDUCATION

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT)

Melbourne, Australia Feb 2019 - Oct 2022

Thesis: Passive visual depth estimation in the deep learning era.

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT)

BSc (Engineering), Adv. Manufacturing and Mechatronics (First Class Honours)

Melbourne, Australia

Mar 2014 - Nov 2018

Projects

RMIT University

PhD (School of Engineering)

Melbourne, Australia

Wide Baseline Stereo Data Collection (Data acquisition, System Integration) Real-time driving imageries data collection using multiple cameras, LiDAR and GPS sensor.

May 2019 - April 2020

RMIT University Melbourne, Australia

Mechatronics Final Year Projects (Computer Vision, Robotics) Development of Statistical SLAM Using Planar Features in 3D Point Clouds Mar 2017 - Oct 2018

SKILLS SUMMARY

Python, C++, MATLAB, Bash • Languages:

• Frameworks: Pandas, Scikit, OpenCV, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch • Tools/Software: Docker, GIT, Jupyter, Carla, CATIA, Solidworks

• Platforms: Linux, Windows, macOS, Arduino, AWS

Extracurricular Experience

High Powered Rocket Team - HIVE RMIT

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

Recovery Systems Team Leader

Develop a reliable rocket recovery system to allow sufficient drag and counteract the force of gravity for minimizing the landing impact. Our team won the first place in the Australian Universities Rocket Competition in the 30,000ft category in 2019.

RMIT Mates Program

Feb 2016 - Oct 2016

Volunteer Mentor

Provide practical advice, social interaction and general academic guidance to newly-arrived international, regional or rural/remote students in their first semester of study at RMIT University.

RMIT Student Learning Advisor Mentors (SLAMs)

Mar 2016 - Jul 2016

Provide academic advice and share strategies with students on time management and study planning to achieve outstanding results.

Referees

Available upon request.